<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dinosaurs Eat Everybody</title>
    <description>For all your Dave Schwantes related needs.</description>    
    <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog</link>
    <atom:link href="http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Fine, I&apos;ll Do It Myself</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I recently moved all my small project sites over to a self-hosted solution using &lt;a href=&quot;https://coolify.io/&quot;&gt;Coolify&lt;/a&gt;. It was pretty easy and really rewarding!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know Heroku still exists, but I miss the generous free tier they offered. This was the perfect solution for spinning up relatively simple, low traffic, Ruby sites, which are what a lot of my projects are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Heroku decided to kick out freeloaders (like me) I started looking around for other hosting options I could mooch from. I ended up moving most of my small sites/projects to &lt;a href=&quot;https://fly.io/&quot;&gt;Fly.io&lt;/a&gt;. When I needed a small database, &lt;a href=&quot;https://supabase.com/&quot;&gt;Supabase&lt;/a&gt; had a pretty good free tier and I ended up using &lt;a href=&quot;https://umami.is/&quot;&gt;Umami&lt;/a&gt; for some simple site analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this all worked pretty well. Fly.io had a good free tier. I only started incurring costs once I was hosting too many sites on my account. Umami worked fine, but the free tier only supported 3 sites and 6 months of data. I did run into a few issues with Fly.io deployments when they changed some configurations, but nothing major. I &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; could have finagled a mostly workable, almost free hosting solution. But near the end of last year, I was fixing the deployment configs for one of my sites and I started thinking, &lt;strong&gt;“Why don’t I do this all myself and have it work exactly the way I want!?”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always a dangerous thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a small Digital Ocean droplet for a while, just to play around with, but I wasn’t doing much with it, so I figured I could use that.  I started looking into “Heroku-like” self-hosting systems and landed on &lt;a href=&quot;https://coolify.io/&quot;&gt;Coolify&lt;/a&gt;. I’m ok with a little DYI, but I didn’t really want to do a lot of serious Linux server maintenance and this seemed to fit the bill.  Setting up Coolify on a Digital Ocean droplet was pretty straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open up some ports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ufw allow 22/tcp
ufw allow 80/tcp
ufw allow 443/tcp
ufw allow 8000/tcp
ufw enable
ufw status
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install Coolify:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -fsSL https://cdn.coollabs.io/coolify/install.sh | bash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I had a web UI to start setting things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each site in Coolify is an application and applications are contained in projects. I ended up setting up two different projects “site” for all the applications that would be normal public facing websites and “tools” for things like analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To handle deploys, Coolify creates a GitHub app that you install on your account and then you give it read permissions on the repos you want to deploy from. This works with both public and private repos. Whenever I push to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch of the sites repo, Coolify gets a webhook and deploys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the sites I was trying to move over were pretty simple Sinatra sites and after a little bit of wresting with the configs (an a lot of asking ChatGPT questions), I got a pretty good pattern down for all the sites I wanted to deploy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create an application that pulls from my GitHub app as a source and launches from a simple Dockerfle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;once the site is deployed, Coolify provides a temporary url to test it out at&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if everything looks good, just change the A record of the domain over to my Digital Ocean droplet’s IP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add the domain name to the Coolfiy application’s config (Coolify handles getting the https certificate!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to keep using Umami for site tracking, but just run my own instance, which ended up being pretty easy.  Coolify lets you create a new application from a public git repo (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://github.com/umami-software/umami&lt;/code&gt; in this case) and sets up the app from that. Coolify also has a simple flow for setting up a new database, so spinning up a Postgres instance for Umami was pretty easy. After getting that set up I moved all my sites over to my own instance of Umami, free of site and data retention limits!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other thing I wanted now that I was self hosting was a little sftp server where I could upload files and have a publicly accessible url for them. To do this I set up an sftp server and then a standalone Nginx server, both pointed as the same persistent storage. Now I don’t need to rely on a 3rd party service if I just want to share a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stuff.toomuchcoffee.dev/dave_sketchy_100.png&quot;&gt;small file&lt;/a&gt;! Not necessary but I did it because it’s my server and I can!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m happy to say I’m self-hosting the sites I run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dinosaurseateverybody.com/&quot;&gt;dinosaurseateverybody.com&lt;/a&gt; (the site you’re looking at right now!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/&quot;&gt;dontbreakprod.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://postwave.blog/&quot;&gt;postwave.blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://evilbrain.band/&quot;&gt;evilbrain.band&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and a few small personal projects and the analytics for those sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not really a big fan of doing dev ops stuff. I have a limited amount of time to spend on personal projects and I’d rather spend that time building and not messing with servers. But there’s something pretty satisfying about hosting your own sites. For me, Coolify was a pretty good paved path to get things up and running with a nice UI.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/fine-ill-do-it-myself</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/fine-ill-do-it-myself</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Postwave</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I probably like writing blog engines more than blog posts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I &lt;a href=&quot;../blog/dont-break-prod&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/&quot;&gt;Don’t Break Prod&lt;/a&gt;, my software engineering career advice site. While I enjoy writing about this stuff, the original motivation for building the site was to test a new blog engine I’d been working on called Postwave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time I’ve been using weird, hacked together solutions to integrate blog posts into my sites. It started with my band and old personal sites where I used WordPress to write posts but then made custom functions to pull the posts directly from the database rather than letting WordPress render a nice site like a normal person would. Later, when I built this version of my site, I did something similar with a Jekyll backend and my &lt;a href=&quot;../blog/sinatra-jekyll-prose&quot;&gt;own custom hooks into the generated html&lt;/a&gt;. I liked being able to write posts in Markdown, but it felt silly to circumvent the whole static site generator to build a dynamic page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did what any impractical programmer would do. I just built my own thing that works exactly the way I want, without any regard for general practicality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where &lt;a href=&quot;https://postwave.blog/&quot;&gt;Postwave&lt;/a&gt; came from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Named after a &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/2J2MincAYeWGK9k4jUzLz1?si=UPA8i-K-RdKI2z6rKKrrZg&quot;&gt;Blue Meanies album&lt;/a&gt; and built to do a very specific thing, Postwave is a fairly simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubygems.org/gems/postwave&quot;&gt;Ruby gem&lt;/a&gt; that lets me write posts in Markdown and then dynamically integrate them into a custom site. When I’m building a small site I usually reach for &lt;a href=&quot;https://sinatrarb.com/&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt;. Most of the time I just want a simple web application with some dynamic endpoints and minimal JavaScript. And then I want a blog engine that just fits into that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postwave gives me simple methods objects and methods so I can use things like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;post.title&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;post.body_html&lt;/code&gt; to build a post display page and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;postwave_client.archive&lt;/code&gt; to get a structured archive.  It also autogenerates an RSS feed for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postwave also has a few simple terminal commands for creating a new posts and “building” the blog, which updates the index, renames files based on post title, generates the RSS file, and a few other things. My workflow for writing posts is just to create a new post in the terminal, write the post in my code editor, rebuild the blog, and deploy the updated site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/postwave1.png &quot; title=&quot;Postwave in the terminal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; (but what little personal project is?), but it is usable. I have an &lt;a href=&quot;https://postwave.blog/&quot;&gt;site/reference implementation&lt;/a&gt; for people to learn about it and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dorkrawk/postwave&quot;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; is available if anyone is interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this site must be using Postwave under the hood, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well… not yet. Dinosaurs Eat Everybody still uses my hacked together Jekyll solution, but that workflow is starting to annoy me so I’m eager to port it over to Postwave now. I’ve been using Postwave for a while on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/&quot;&gt;Don’t Break Prod&lt;/a&gt; so I feel pretty confident that it’s ready for use elsewhere. I’d like to build some small tools to make it easy to migrate a Jekyll site to Postwave. The post format is very similar and it would just make my migration easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postwave has been a great little “scratch your own itch” project for me. I’m looking forward to using it more for my own blogging needs. And if my problems sound similar to yours, &lt;a href=&quot;https://postwave.blog/&quot;&gt;try it out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/postwave</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/postwave</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Random Thoughts About AI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just what the world needs, another software engineer pontificating about AI!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing too deep here, just some things I’ve been mulling over that aren’t worth writing whole posts about…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are we all really going to be staff engineers?&lt;/strong&gt; It seems like there are a lot of people (or companies?) pushing the idea that the future of software engineering is making design decisions and directing and correcting a bunch of agents to get the work done. This sounds a lot like what some staff engineers do. What does a junior staff engineer even look like? It seems like this whole idea relies on people being good at clear communication and multitasking (two things that are very easy to screw up).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I hate that everything requires a subscription.&lt;/strong&gt; If coding with a state of the art LLM becomes the default, it means that by default coding will involve paying a monthly subscription. While companies will probably provide this for employees, there’s now a perceived cost barrier for just wanting to build something on your own. It feels like model providers are hoping LLMs just become another utility that everybody needs to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s a difference between wanting something made and wanting to make something.&lt;/strong&gt; Coding agents are fantastic for getting something to exist. I have absolutely used them to take on coding projects that I just didn’t want to bother with. One of my favorite LLM uses at work with handling the boiler plate around new tests. It would be silly to say that AI isn’t useful for making things exist. But sometimes you want to &lt;em&gt;make things&lt;/em&gt; and doing that with heavy agent usage just feels kind of hollow. The feeling of accomplishment that you get from building something yourself is real and there’s a cost to losing it. Sometimes I just need a table so I just buy one from Ikea, but that’s a different experience than using a piece of furniture that you designed and built yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI can be really useful for learning, but you have to choose to use it for learning rather than just getting stuff done.&lt;/strong&gt; Before you could get an agent to just build something for you, you had to get your hands dirty building it yourself. This often required either learning something new up front or incidentally learning something along the way. Now you have to consciously decide you’re going to learn (which AI can help with!) in addition to shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We haven’t seen AI products really enshitify yet.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s not going to be fun…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/random-thoughts-about-ai</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/random-thoughts-about-ai</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Just Use a Laptop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My most millennial trait is that big purchases must happen in a big laptop screen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should just use a laptop. For most things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phones (and tablets, to some degree) are amazing because they’re a powerful computing device that is always with you, but they’re kind of awful for that same reason. When you can always pull out your phone to take care of a task, do your shopping, etc. you’re always trying to do multiple things at once. If you can do it now you never have the excuse to plan to do it later. This has two pretty crappy consequences:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;you never have to prioritize things&lt;/strong&gt;. You just do them as soon you think of them. Maybe you’re multitasking during dinner to get things done that don’t actually matter. If you can keep checking Slack for work, you never have to decide you’re done for the day. It can feel good to cram a little bit of productivity into gaps into your downtime, but sometimes it’s good to have downtime. Being busy is not a virtue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And second, &lt;strong&gt;it’s harder to fully focus on your task&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’re reading emails or doing your shopping while you’re out with other people you’re only half doing both things. The double edged sword of using your phone for everything is that it’s always with you, so you don’t need to go to a dedicated “work space” to do your tasks. The inconvenience of getting out a laptop and opening it up to work is a feature. I think there’s a lot of value in getting in the right head space to do non-trivial tasks and if you’re primary device for getting things done is optimized for convenience rather than focus you’re going to spend more time on the types of tasks that don’t require deep focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phones are great tools for a lot of things. They are really well optimized for portability (obviously), simplistic input, and consumption. The fact that I can get map directions or watch a movie wherever I am is a modern miracle. I love that I can pull out my phone whenever I get a random song idea and record a voice memo before I forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don’t want to do the work of turning an idea into a finished song on my phone. For that I want to sit in a quiet place with instruments and a proper recording interface. It’s not just that the tools are better with richer input mechanisms and more screen space for powerful UIs. The act of deciding to be in a “songwriting place” helps get my head into the task. It means I’m focused on one task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’ll even wait until I’m at a laptop to make non-trivial responses to text messages. Trying to type a paragraph or more on a phone keyboard feels like squeezing ideas through a straw, it just feels easier to type on a real keyboard with richer options for copying, pasting, and other text manipulation. Sure, if I’m out of the house and need to message someone, it’s great to be able to just send something from my phone, but it’s not an interface optimized for longer-form text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tablets are an interesting middle ground, but in many ways they still encourage more consumption than focused work. Attaching a keyboard can help. If you’re mainly trying to write emails, watch videos, and look at websites it’s probably ok, but you’re still using a device that is optimized for scrolling and tapping. There are some use cases where a tablet might be superior to a proper computer, such as drawing. If I were doing comics right now an iPad with &lt;a href=&quot;https://procreate.com/&quot;&gt;Procreate&lt;/a&gt; seems like it would be the best tool for the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t dislike phones (or tablets). They’re amazing and useful tools. I just think that the habit many people have of pulling out a phone to accomplish whatever tasks happens to come to mind creates a world where you’re always kind of multitasking and rarely sitting down to focus on things. Embrace the inconvenience of using a computer that might not be in your pocket at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just use a laptop. For most things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/just-use-a-laptop</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/just-use-a-laptop</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Playing With Linux</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I’ve been thinking more about making computers/the internet &lt;a href=&quot;../blog/pragmatic-divesting-from-enshitifcation&quot;&gt;fun again&lt;/a&gt;. Part of this was trying to use more technology without an “agenda”. And that has led me into the arms of Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I picked up a &lt;a href=&quot;https://frame.work/laptop13&quot;&gt;Framework 13&lt;/a&gt; laptop so I’d have a Windows machine to play Minecraft on with my kid. It’s been useful to have around, but Windows 11 was just glaringly aggressive with how much it wanted me to sign up for various Microsoft services. I probably hadn’t used a Windows computer for anything non-trivial since Windows 7 and the change was striking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the urge to try dual booting Linux on my Framework so I installed Ubuntu and used DHH’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://omakub.org/&quot;&gt;Omakub&lt;/a&gt; to get it set up quickly. It was kind of fun and I’ve been using as my primary dev machine for working on &lt;a href=&quot;../blog/building-a-programming-language-in-crystal&quot;&gt;Lox&lt;/a&gt;. Having a project has been helpful for just exploring the system a bit and I found myself switching back and forth between Windows and Ubuntu pretty often on that computer. Omakub really did a good job of making things look nice and providing some good defaults so I didn’t spend a ton of time getting things set up and usable. I dug in to using Neovim as my editor and Alacritty as my terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s nice to have things both configured AND configurable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw DHH posting about &lt;a href=&quot;https://omarchy.org/&quot;&gt;Omarchy&lt;/a&gt; I was interested. Arch always seemed a little intimidating and I wanted to spend my time using my computer, not fixing/configuring it so having some good defaults and a little hand-holding on the install seemed nice. Due to some disk encryption requirements you’re not able to (easily) dual boot Omarchy right now, so I didn’t think I could replace my Ubuntu setup but my curiosity got the best of me. I found an old 2012 MacBook Air, bought a USB-Ethernet adapter (so I could run the install without wifi working), and put the ISO on a thumb drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation was surprisingly easy. I expected to run into some wifi issues but everything worked out of the box. Having played around with the Omakub setup on my Ubuntu install, I felt pretty comfortable with a lot of the default applications like neovim and Alacritty as well as some shortcuts like Super-space for the app launcher so that helped a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hypr.land/&quot;&gt;Hyprland&lt;/a&gt; felt like more of an adjustment. This was my first time really using a tiling window manager. I use Rectangle on my Macs for some basic window resizing and positioning but this was the first time I’d really working in a purely tiled desktop. I tend to have a chaotic pile of windows on my screen most of the time so in some ways using a tiled window manager helped me avoid that because if I kept too many things open, the new windows were uselessly small. If I needed more space I used additional desktops or even just closed windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus on using built in (and configurable) keyboard shortcuts for launching common programs really helped (Super-Return for a terminal, Super-B for a browser, etc.). It made it feel more natural to quickly open things when I needed them and close them when I was done. I also really like the use of “web app windows”, these are basically keyboard shortcuts to open up web apps (like email, Twitter, etc.) in chromeless browser windows via keyboard shortcut. Super-C to open a quick Google Calendar window is really nice and I’ve created and customized a few new shortcuts for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what about really hacking around with Arch? Well, I haven’t done a bunch of power user stuff yet and honestly I don’t plan on spending a lot of time futzing around with things. I still want to spend most of my time using my computer, not fixing/configuring it. I did put in a little time getting the display to rescale nicely when I plugged into a large monitor and closed the laptop to work in clamshell mode. It was fun to see how much control I had over things, if I wanted it. I might also look into some fun widgets that work with Waybar and Hyprland to display some useful into if I have the time and inclination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s nice to have things both configured and REALLY configurable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, am I going to cast off the oppressive shackles of MacOS and Windows so I can live exclusively in the land of the Free and Open Source? Eh, probably not. There are a few reasons I’ll keep using my Mac and have at least a Windows partition somewhere:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My M1 MacBook Pro is one of the nicest feeling laptops I’ve ever used.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s fast, it feels solid, and everything just works.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logic&lt;/strong&gt; I use Logic for all my music recording. A lot of the people I make music with use Logic. I’m not going to switch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I use iMessage on a laptop a lot.&lt;/strong&gt; I don’t like typing long text messages on my phone, so I often switch to my laptop to send non-trivial things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occasionally I’ll find a game I want to play that’s only on Windows (and/or Mac)&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m not a big gamer, and gaming on Linux seems to be getting better, but there are certainly some interesting things that come out that just don’t work in Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes I want things to just work.&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe that’s a fingerprint reader or my Plex server, but I don’t have as much time to fiddle with things anymore so there are many situations where I’m going to use the tools that get (and keep) me up and running with the least amount of effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I do think I’ll use this Omarchy set up a fair amount. I replaced the battery in my Omarchy computer and it’s turned this 15 year old laptop into a very usable machine. I like that my computing environment doesn’t feel like it has an “agenda”. It’s not trying to sell me on any services, just “here’s an OS, try not to get yourself killed.” It feels more like a powerful tool than a product, which is nice these days. Also, it’s just fun to learn something different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m enjoying using Linux and that kinda matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/omarchy-air.png&quot; title=&quot;I use Arch, by the way.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/playing-with-linux</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/playing-with-linux</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another And Or Not Record</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody asked for it, but it got made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/stereoscopic400.png &quot; title=&quot;Stereoscopic cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month I put out a new EP from my solo project, And Or Not. If you want to skip the self indulgent dive into making this recording and just go listen to it, you can just go &lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/stereoscopic&quot;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;&quot; src=&quot;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3482022036/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/stereoscopic&quot;&gt;Stereoscopic by And Or Not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../blog/and-or-not&quot;&gt;And Or Not&lt;/a&gt; is an exercise in simplistic instrumentation. It’s only bass, drums, vocals, and some keys for a little added texture. It’s a nice balance to the more complex arrangements of things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/4hb8s9fy6ws3H94zyZfgY7?si=3wyoxPn5R5yBGYi80yHFoQ&quot;&gt;Grave Danger&lt;/a&gt;. Like last time I started by just writing a bunch of bass riffs, recording them into one big project, and then coming back later to pick out ones I liked to build songs around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’d massaged those riffs into basic song structures I started putting some lyrics together. I’ve given myself a lot of leeway to write about whatever pops into my mind so I ended up writing about &lt;a href=&quot;../blog/pragmatic-divesting-from-enshitifcation&quot;&gt;my disappointment around the current state of the internet&lt;/a&gt; (Let’s Get Weird Again), Minecraft (Bedrock), and coffee (Top Me Off).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the recording process, I took the demos I made for writing, mapped it to a click and started by laying down the drums. I think I’m a better drummer than I was when I did the first record but it still took a while to get everything down since I was sort of writing parts while I was trying to record them. I think I’ve gotten a little better at recording drums, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bass parts were pretty straightforward to lay down, but I spent a little more time layering my tone. After seeing ‘68 live I got inspired to lean into a noisier, fuzzier sound and not be afraid to build up a more complex tone. I’m using bass amp models from Logic for my tone so I ended up taking the raw tracks and running them through three different amp setups (resulting in 3 tracks for all the bass parts). One track had a really fuzzy tone, one beefed up the low end, and a third focused on brightening the attack. Mixed together I got a really full sound, which was pretty important when there isn’t much else in terms of instrumentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did add some keys, mainly B3 organ, to thicken things up and add a bit of counter melody in a few parts, but it was pretty minimal. Mainly just to add some more texture to the songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, vocals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still not very confident about my vocals, but doing a solo project means that it can just be whatever I put down so I’ve been digging into it. I had a lot of fun layering and doing harmonies on these songs. I also tried to put in a few more “character” elements (“wooo”s, “let’s go!”s, etc.) to help combat the very “studio only” nature of these recordings (since I’m the band, these songs have never been played live). Doing vocals for this project has very much been an exercise in just laying stuff down and putting it out there with as much confidence as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though this is my solo project I always love getting my kids in on songs so I had Elliot come in and record some extra vocals on Bedrock. We’ve been playing a lot of Minecraft lately and it seemed appropriate to get him in that song somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite little easter egg on this record came from Max. If you listen really carefully at the end of the last song (Top Me Off), you can hear him say “Ok, can we play cars now?”. I had been recording drums when he came down and wanted to play. He let me do one more take, waited very patiently, and after the last hit excitedly asked if we could play now. I thought it was a great little incidental moment so I left it in, isolated it, and turned it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover art was, somewhat begrudgingly, done with ChatGPT. I knew kind of how I wanted it to look and managed to get a full cover together in only a few minutes. Part of me wishes I had made it from scratch, just out of principle, but I got something I’m happy with and that’s what matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m really proud of this EP. It took WAY longer than it should have to complete because I could only work on it in fits and bursts when I had free time (and could be loud at home). It feels like good progress for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/the-infernal-machine&quot;&gt;previous record&lt;/a&gt; and, honestly, I just love putting out music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/stereoscopic&quot;&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/another-and-or-not-record</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/another-and-or-not-record</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building A Programming Language In Crystal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After doing a rotation on GitHub’s “Ruby Architecture” team a few years ago and learning more about how programming languages really work (and getting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruby/ruby/pull/6078&quot;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruby/ruby/pull/6079&quot;&gt;commits&lt;/a&gt; into the Ruby language myself) I’ve been trying to learn more about building languages. For the last year or so I’ve been very slowly working my way through the first half of &lt;a href=&quot;https://craftinginterpreters.com/&quot;&gt;Crafting Interpreters&lt;/a&gt; by Robert Nystrom, which has been a fantastic book on the topic. It starts by walking you step by step through the implementation of a language designed for the book called Lox. The book builds the language in Java, but I chose to implement it in &lt;a href=&quot;https://crystal-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Crystal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why Crystal? I like it. It’s syntax looks very Ruby-like but it has static (and sometimes explicit) typing. It’s reasonably fast when compiled. Plus, by implementing all the examples in a different language it forced me to understand what I was doing enough to translate from Java to Crystal. I’m not the first person to implement a Lox interpreter in Crystal, but it is a less common project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a “toy” language built as a learning tool, Lox implements some nontrivial things. A simple “Hello world” looks as expected:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;print &quot;Hello world!&quot;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has loops! While loops and for loops (which are turned into while loops by the interpreter):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;var k = 30;
while(k &amp;lt; 40) {
  print k;
  k = k + 1;
}

for(var j = 30; j &amp;lt; 40; j = j + 1) {
    print j;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it has objects and inheritance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class Animal {
  init(name) {
    this.name = name;
  }
}

class Cat &amp;lt; Animal {
  meow() {
    print &quot;meow&quot;;
  }
}

var kitten = Cat(&quot;Mochi&quot;);
kitten.meow();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this all feels like pretty standard stuff for any programming language you might use, it was really cool to build everything up from scratch. The parser was written from scratch in less than 500 lines of code, no using any big libraries like Bison or Yacc. The scanner handles a little over 40 tokens in less than 200 lines of code. It has a resolver to handle some scope ambiguities and static analysis. This is just been a really cool project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to all the cool programming language stuff I learned working on this I also used this project as an excuse to develop in Neovim on the Ubuntu laptop I set up a while ago (using DHH’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://omakub.org/&quot;&gt;Omakub&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the code being a little messy in parts (sometimes I got impatient trying to handle Nils in Crystal) and containing some bugs, I’m sure, it’s still really cool have this project in a “done” state. I might come back later and clean up the code or add some features (this implementation of Lox lacks a way to take user input…) but for now I’m going to move on to the next section of the book where I’ll build Lox again, this time as a more optimized, compiled language implemented in C (I probably haven’t touched C since college…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, check out my implementation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dorkrawk/crlox&quot;&gt;crlox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/building-a-programming-language-in-crystal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/building-a-programming-language-in-crystal</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Pizza</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like making pizza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started it was pretty arduous. I actually had to grind the wheat to make flour for the dough. Making the cheese took forever. Toppings were a luxury unless I could find someone else who was making them and even then they could be really expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time went on, things got easier, though. I was able to buy bags of nice flour. Cheese was easy to get and a wide range of toppings became available. If I was really in a hurry, I could even find pre-made sauces that were pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more people got into making pizza so there were lots of new recipes out there to try, which was fun too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I started seeing pre-made dough and even full kits with dough sauce and toppings ready to assemble and bake, which was pretty nice when I was in a hurry and just wanted something basic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then pizza delivery services popped up. I could just order whatever kind of pizza I wanted and it would show up at my door, faster than I could make one myself! Some of them were pretty good and it’s a really easy way to get dinner when you’re too busy to cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have pizza whenever I want, which is pretty cool. I probably eat pizza more often now than I ever have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I don’t really make pizza anymore, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🍕&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/making-pizza</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/making-pizza</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pragmatic Divesting From Enshitifcation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of people noticing that &lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralistic.net/2023/01/21/potemkin-ai/#hey-guys&quot;&gt;the internet isn’t as fun as it used to be&lt;/a&gt;. Not that it was perfect in the past, but there’s a sense that what was once weird and quirky and full of potential (while still having a number of rough edges) is now mean and manipulative and controlled by a small number of large companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of the more tech savvy people who are feeling this, there’s a lot of push to leave all of these unpleasant places behind and live entirely in alternative spaces. This might mean getting Google out of your life, leaving &lt;span title=&quot;I just can&apos;t call it &apos;X&apos;, that&apos;s just such a dumb name...&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/span&gt; or Facebook or whatever major platform. But that’s hard if you want to interact with people who don’t think about tech all the time. It’s the digital equivalent of homesteading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to be more conscious about trying to make my online life more pleasant in pragmatic ways. Ways that make me happier without feeling isolated from my less tech focused friends. More “growing some of my own food at home” and less “moving into a cabin in the woods”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actual Social Networks&lt;/strong&gt;
I’ve never found Twitter or Instagram to be particularly toxic places and I think that’s because I’ve used them in an odd way. I only really follow people I know personally and I try my best to avoid algorithmically suggested posts. I will sometimes manually visit the profiles of interesting accounts, but the extra friction prevents me from passively consuming everything they post in perpetuity. This means my feeds on these sites are mainly friends and old coworkers who I actually like. I’m sure I’m missing a lot of funny videos and maybe some interesting content, but I think I’m happier this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tending My Own Garden&lt;/strong&gt;
That said, I’ve been less inclined to engage on other people’s platforms lately. The internet was weirder and more fun when it wasn’t just people posting to handful of huge sites. I’ve been writing more on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/&quot;&gt;Don’t Break Prod&lt;/a&gt; and doing more little &lt;a href=&quot;../now&quot;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt; to this site, with the plan to share more things here. Again I haven’t deactivated my accounts on any major sites, I’m just not really interested in building my castle in other people’s kingdoms (even if that costs me priceless things like “engagement”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s Get Weird Again&lt;/strong&gt;
Finally, I’m looking around more for weird fun things on the internet. People just building stuff because they wanted to see it exist. While a lot of the internet feels mean or angry or hustle focused or just un-fun in a lot of ways, there are still lots of people who just want to make cool stuff and share it. It’s out there if you just poke around a little bit. I’m hoping the stuff I put out there contributes just a little to making the internet a bit weirder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it’s just rose colored glasses that make me think that the internet was more fun in the past. While many things have gotten better, something valuable has been lost. You can’t go back, but you can focus on the things that make you happy and minimize the things that don’t. It’s not as bold a statement as dramatically quitting Facebook only talking to your friends who use &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;, but the internet can still be fun if you just don’t wallow in the worst parts of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/pragmatic-divesting-from-enshitifcation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/pragmatic-divesting-from-enshitifcation</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don&apos;t Break Prod</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This all started with my irrational desire to build yet another blogging engine. The world doesn’t have enough of those right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll go into more detail about the software I built in a future post, but long story short I built a little blogging tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dorkrawk/postwave&quot;&gt;Postwave&lt;/a&gt; and I needed a site to put it through its paces. I needed something that I could make frequent posts to and see what it was like to really use what I had built. So I created &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/&quot;&gt;Don’t Break Prod&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of bite sized pieces of career advice for software engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about mentorship and ways to have a good life as a software engineer for a long time. I have a bunch of notes and a decent outline for a book of engineering mentorship that I started and lost steam on a few years ago as well as insights gained from being both a mentor and mentee. Eileen and I have had great conversations about career stuff that I often walk away from with good insights. So I started writing down a list of ideas about how to make your life better as a software engineer. These range from simple technical ideas like, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/posts/embrace-linters&quot;&gt;embracing linters&lt;/a&gt; to broader ideas about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/posts/dont-burn-out&quot;&gt;avoiding burnout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind Don’t Break Prod is to do short form posts, something longer than a tweet but shorter than a full blog post. The title should give you the basic advice, the content should provide some food for thought around it. This has also lowered the activation energy for me to write new posts regularly, which helps a lot. I’ve deliberately avoided having a comment section because while I want people to read these and engage with them, I really didn’t feel like managing a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not really sure what my big picture goals are for &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/&quot;&gt;Don’t Break Prod&lt;/a&gt;. It’s doing a good job as a testing ground for Postwave and in a time where it feels like most content just exists on a few social networks it feels good to be writing directly on a site run myself. As for the content of the site, I think that having a career tha makes you happy and fits into your life the way you want is important. Thinking about these posts has helped me articulate ideas that are useful for me and I hope other people find them valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’ve been sporadically posting to the site for a few years now, I’ve recently been getting a little more serious about making regular posts and trying to share them more broadly. I’d love to reach as many people as possible, as long as I can keep writing posts and promoting them in my own weird way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/dont-break-prod</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/dont-break-prod</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
