<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dinosaurs Eat Everybody</title>
    <description>For all your Dave Schwantes related needs.</description>    
    <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog</link>
    <atom:link href="http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Another And Or Not Record</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody asked for it, but it got made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/stereoscopic400.png &quot; title=&quot;Stereoscopic cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month I put out a new EP from my solo project, And Or Not. If you want to skip the self indulgent dive into making this recording and just go listen to it, you can just go &lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/stereoscopic&quot;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;&quot; src=&quot;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3482022036/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/stereoscopic&quot;&gt;Stereoscopic by And Or Not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../blog/and-or-not&quot;&gt;And Or Not&lt;/a&gt; is an exercise in simplistic instrumentation. It’s only bass, drums, vocals, and some keys for a little added texture. It’s a nice balance to the more complex arrangements of things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/4hb8s9fy6ws3H94zyZfgY7?si=3wyoxPn5R5yBGYi80yHFoQ&quot;&gt;Grave Danger&lt;/a&gt;. Like last time I started by just writing a bunch of bass riffs, recording them into one big project, and then coming back later to pick out ones I liked to build songs around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’d massaged those riffs into basic song structures I started putting some lyrics together. I’ve given myself a lot of leeway to write about whatever pops into my mind so I ended up writing about &lt;a href=&quot;../blog/pragmatic-divesting-from-enshitifcation&quot;&gt;my disappointment around the current state of the internet&lt;/a&gt; (Let’s Get Weird Again), Minecraft (Bedrock), and coffee (Top Me Off).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the recording process, I took the demos I made for writing, mapped it to a click and started by laying down the drums. I think I’m a better drummer than I was when I did the first record but it still took a while to get everything down since I was sort of writing parts while I was trying to record them. I think I’ve gotten a little better at recording drums, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bass parts were pretty straightforward to lay down, but I spent a little more time layering my tone. After seeing ‘68 live I got inspired to lean into a noisier, fuzzier sound and not be afraid to build up a more complex tone. I’m using bass amp models from Logic for my tone so I ended up taking the raw tracks and running them through three different amp setups (resulting in 3 tracks for all the bass parts). One track had a really fuzzy tone, one beefed up the low end, and a third focused on brightening the attack. Mixed together I got a really full sound, which was pretty important when there isn’t much else in terms of instrumentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did add some keys, mainly B3 organ, to thicken things up and add a bit of counter melody in a few parts, but it was pretty minimal. Mainly just to add some more texture to the songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, vocals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still not very confident about my vocals, but doing a solo project means that it can just be whatever I put down so I’ve been digging into it. I had a lot of fun layering and doing harmonies on these songs. I also tried to put in a few more “character” elements (“wooo”s, “let’s go!”s, etc.) to help combat the very “studio only” nature of these recordings (since I’m the band, these songs have never been played live). Doing vocals for this project has very much been an exercise in just laying stuff down and putting it out there with as much confidence as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though this is my solo project I always love getting my kids in on songs so I had Elliot come in and record some extra vocals on Bedrock. We’ve been playing a lot of Minecraft lately and it seemed appropriate to get him in that song somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite little easter egg on this record came from Max. If you listen really carefully at the end of the last song (Top Me Off), you can hear him say “Ok, can we play cars now?”. I had been recording drums when he came down and wanted to play. He let me do one more take, waited very patiently, and after the last hit excitedly asked if we could play now. I thought it was a great little incidental moment so I left it in, isolated it, and turned it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover art was, somewhat begrudgingly, done with ChatGPT. I knew kind of how I wanted it to look and managed to get a full cover together in only a few minutes. Part of me wishes I had made it from scratch, just out of principle, but I got something I’m happy with and that’s what matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m really proud of this EP. It took WAY longer than it should have to complete because I could only work on it in fits and bursts when I had free time (and could be loud at home). It feels like good progress for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/the-infernal-machine&quot;&gt;previous record&lt;/a&gt; and, honestly, I just love putting out music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/stereoscopic&quot;&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/another-and-or-not-record</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/another-and-or-not-record</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building A Programming Language In Crystal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After doing a rotation on GitHub’s “Ruby Architecture” team a few years ago and learning more about how programming languages really work (and getting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruby/ruby/pull/6078&quot;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruby/ruby/pull/6079&quot;&gt;commits&lt;/a&gt; into the Ruby language myself) I’ve been trying to learn more about building languages. For the last year or so I’ve been very slowly working my way through the first half of &lt;a href=&quot;https://craftinginterpreters.com/&quot;&gt;Crafting Interpreters&lt;/a&gt; by Robert Nystrom, which has been a fantastic book on the topic. It starts by walking you step by step through the implementation of a language designed for the book called Lox. The book builds the language in Java, but I chose to implement it in &lt;a href=&quot;https://crystal-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Crystal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why Crystal? I like it. It’s syntax looks very Ruby-like but it has static (and sometimes explicit) typing. It’s reasonably fast when compiled. Plus, by implementing all the examples in a different language it forced me to understand what I was doing enough to translate from Java to Crystal. I’m not the first person to implement a Lox interpreter in Crystal, but it is a less common project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a “toy” language built as a learning tool, Lox implements some nontrivial things. A simple “Hello world” looks as expected:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;print &quot;Hello world!&quot;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has loops! While loops and for loops (which are turned into while loops by the interpreter):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;var k = 30;
while(k &amp;lt; 40) {
  print k;
  k = k + 1;
}

for(var j = 30; j &amp;lt; 40; j = j + 1) {
    print j;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it has objects and inheritance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class Animal {
  init(name) {
    this.name = name;
  }
}

class Cat &amp;lt; Animal {
  meow() {
    print &quot;meow&quot;;
  }
}

var kitten = Cat(&quot;Mochi&quot;);
kitten.meow();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this all feels like pretty standard stuff for any programming language you might use, it was really cool to build everything up from scratch. The parser was written from scratch in less than 500 lines of code, no using any big libraries like Bison or Yacc. The scanner handles a little over 40 tokens in less than 200 lines of code. It has a resolver to handle some scope ambiguities and static analysis. This is just been a really cool project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to all the cool programming language stuff I learned working on this I also used this project as an excuse to develop in Neovim on the Ubuntu laptop I set up a while ago (using DHH’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://omakub.org/&quot;&gt;Omakub&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the code being a little messy in parts (sometimes I got impatient trying to handle Nils in Crystal) and containing some bugs, I’m sure, it’s still really cool have this project in a “done” state. I might come back later and clean up the code or add some features (this implementation of Lox lacks a way to take user input…) but for now I’m going to move on to the next section of the book where I’ll build Lox again, this time as a more optimized, compiled language implemented in C (I probably haven’t touched C since college…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, check out my implementation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dorkrawk/crlox&quot;&gt;crlox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/building-a-programming-language-in-crystal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/building-a-programming-language-in-crystal</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Pizza</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like making pizza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started it was pretty arduous. I actually had to grind the wheat to make flour for the dough. Making the cheese took forever. Toppings were a luxury unless I could find someone else who was making them and even then they could be really expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time went on, things got easier, though. I was able to buy bags of nice flour. Cheese was easy to get and a wide range of toppings became available. If I was really in a hurry, I could even find pre-made sauces that were pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more people got into making pizza so there were lots of new recipes out there to try, which was fun too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I started seeing pre-made dough and even full kits with dough sauce and toppings ready to assemble and bake, which was pretty nice when I was in a hurry and just wanted something basic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then pizza delivery services popped up. I could just order whatever kind of pizza I wanted and it would show up at my door, faster than I could make one myself! Some of them were pretty good and it’s a really easy way to get dinner when you’re too busy to cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have pizza whenever I want, which is pretty cool. I probably eat pizza more often now than I ever have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I don’t really make pizza anymore, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🍕&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/making-pizza</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/making-pizza</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pragmatic Divesting From Enshitifcation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of people noticing that &lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralistic.net/2023/01/21/potemkin-ai/#hey-guys&quot;&gt;the internet isn’t as fun as it used to be&lt;/a&gt;. Not that it was perfect in the past, but there’s a sense that what was once weird and quirky and full of potential (while still having a number of rough edges) is now mean and manipulative and controlled by a small number of large companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of the more tech savvy people who are feeling this, there’s a lot of push to leave all of these unpleasant places behind and live entirely in alternative spaces. This might mean getting Google out of your life, leaving &lt;span title=&quot;I just can&apos;t call it &apos;X&apos;, that&apos;s just such a dumb name...&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/span&gt; or Facebook or whatever major platform. But that’s hard if you want to interact with people who don’t think about tech all the time. It’s the digital equivalent of homesteading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to be more conscious about trying to make my online life more pleasant in pragmatic ways. Ways that make me happier without feeling isolated from my less tech focused friends. More “growing some of my own food at home” and less “moving into a cabin in the woods”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actual Social Networks&lt;/strong&gt;
I’ve never found Twitter or Instagram to be particularly toxic places and I think that’s because I’ve used them in an odd way. I only really follow people I know personally and I try my best to avoid algorithmically suggested posts. I will sometimes manually visit the profiles of interesting accounts, but the extra friction prevents me from passively consuming everything they post in perpetuity. This means my feeds on these sites are mainly friends and old coworkers who I actually like. I’m sure I’m missing a lot of funny videos and maybe some interesting content, but I think I’m happier this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tending My Own Garden&lt;/strong&gt;
That said, I’ve been less inclined to engage on other people’s platforms lately. The internet was weirder and more fun when it wasn’t just people posting to handful of huge sites. I’ve been writing more on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/&quot;&gt;Don’t Break Prod&lt;/a&gt; and doing more little &lt;a href=&quot;../now&quot;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt; to this site, with the plan to share more things here. Again I haven’t deactivated my accounts on any major sites, I’m just not really interested in building my castle in other people’s kingdoms (even if that costs me priceless things like “engagement”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s Get Weird Again&lt;/strong&gt;
Finally, I’m looking around more for weird fun things on the internet. People just building stuff because they wanted to see it exist. While a lot of the internet feels mean or angry or hustle focused or just un-fun in a lot of ways, there are still lots of people who just want to make cool stuff and share it. It’s out there if you just poke around a little bit. I’m hoping the stuff I put out there contributes just a little to making the internet a bit weirder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it’s just rose colored glasses that make me think that the internet was more fun in the past. While many things have gotten better, something valuable has been lost. You can’t go back, but you can focus on the things that make you happy and minimize the things that don’t. It’s not as bold a statement as dramatically quitting Facebook only talking to your friends who use &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;, but the internet can still be fun if you just don’t wallow in the worst parts of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/pragmatic-divesting-from-enshitifcation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/pragmatic-divesting-from-enshitifcation</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don&apos;t Break Prod</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This all started with my irrational desire to build yet another blogging engine. The world doesn’t have enough of those right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll go into more detail about the software I built in a future post, but long story short I built a little blogging tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dorkrawk/postwave&quot;&gt;Postwave&lt;/a&gt; and I needed a site to put it through its paces. I needed something that I could make frequent posts to and see what it was like to really use what I had built. So I created &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/&quot;&gt;Don’t Break Prod&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of bite sized pieces of career advice for software engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about mentorship and ways to have a good life as a software engineer for a long time. I have a bunch of notes and a decent outline for a book of engineering mentorship that I started and lost steam on a few years ago as well as insights gained from being both a mentor and mentee. Eileen and I have had great conversations about career stuff that I often walk away from with good insights. So I started writing down a list of ideas about how to make your life better as a software engineer. These range from simple technical ideas like, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/posts/embrace-linters&quot;&gt;embracing linters&lt;/a&gt; to broader ideas about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/posts/dont-burn-out&quot;&gt;avoiding burnout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind Don’t Break Prod is to do short form posts, something longer than a tweet but shorter than a full blog post. The title should give you the basic advice, the content should provide some food for thought around it. This has also lowered the activation energy for me to write new posts regularly, which helps a lot. I’ve deliberately avoided having a comment section because while I want people to read these and engage with them, I really didn’t feel like managing a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not really sure what my big picture goals are for &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontbreakprod.com/&quot;&gt;Don’t Break Prod&lt;/a&gt;. It’s doing a good job as a testing ground for Postwave and in a time where it feels like most content just exists on a few social networks it feels good to be writing directly on a site run myself. As for the content of the site, I think that having a career tha makes you happy and fits into your life the way you want is important. Thinking about these posts has helped me articulate ideas that are useful for me and I hope other people find them valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’ve been sporadically posting to the site for a few years now, I’ve recently been getting a little more serious about making regular posts and trying to share them more broadly. I’d love to reach as many people as possible, as long as I can keep writing posts and promoting them in my own weird way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/dont-break-prod</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/dont-break-prod</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Homeboard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I always forget to move my car on street cleaning day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 1st Wednesday of the month I was always scrambling to move my street-parked car in the hopes of avoiding a ticket. Often too late. So I wanted something I looked at every day to remind me of things like this, just a little dashboard in my kitchen to let me know what was going on during the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this isn’t a particularly novel idea and I’m sure there are a few out of the box products that will do this, I just though it would be fun to build something custom for what I wanted. It ended up being a small Sinatra app and I decided to play around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmx.org/&quot;&gt;htmx&lt;/a&gt; for most of the dynamic frontend stuff. The basic features I wanted were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a big clock (date and time)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;local weather&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a QR code to log on to our local wifi network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;events for today and tomorrow:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;city events (street cleaning, garbage day, snow plowing, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;birthdays (I don’t look at Facebook enough anymore for it to be a reliable reminder)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;our shared Google calendar&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what it ended up looking like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/homeboard2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these were pretty simple. The clock is just some plain old Javascript running client side. Birthdays come from a big hardcoded Hash that just looks up date. The city events came from some hardcoded logic based on the date, things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# first Wednesday of the month&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;applicable&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;STREET_CLEANING_MONTH_RANGE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;include?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;timestamp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;timestamp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;wednesday?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;timestamp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;tuesday?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;timestamp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;mday&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The QR code just seemed like a neat little feature. You can create QR codes that when scanned will allow you to join a local wifi network without manually entering the password. I just generated my code from something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qr-code-generator.com/solutions/wifi-qr-code/&quot;&gt;this site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For local weather I ended up making use of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openweathermap.org/api&quot;&gt;OpenWeather API&lt;/a&gt;. It refreshes infrequently enough that I can use it for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google Calendar integration gave me the most trouble. For some reason it was WAY more of a pain in the ass to authenticate with Google and use the provided library to pull a list of calendar events than I figured it would be. It involved a lot of creating and refreshing access tokens and is still a little janky (but it work!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I started doing the dynamic front end stuff with vanilla Javascript I ended up rewriting almost everything in Htmx, mainly because it seemed interesting and I wanted to play around with it. For the VERY simple stuff I was doing (mainly periodically refreshing parts of the dashboard to get updated content) it was very clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I want my weather to reload every hour so on the main dashboard page (the page that stays up all the time) there’s a div that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;content_box weather_box&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;hx-get=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;../api/weather_htmx&quot;&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;hx-trigger=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;load, every 3600s&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just pulls the contents of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/api/weather_htmx&lt;/code&gt; (which is just some html, rendered with the updated weather info from an API call to OpenWeather) and puts it inside that div. Magic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a cheap refurbished tablet to use as a display and it’s been a great addition to our kitchen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/homeboard1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/homeboard</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/homeboard</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I added a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dinosaurseateverybody.com/now&quot;&gt;Now&lt;/a&gt; page to this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of a now page to write up what you’re doing right now. Basically what you’d tell someone if you were catching up and they asked “So what have you been up to lately?”. The idea has been attributed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sive.rs/now&quot;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt; (who apparently is the guy who created CD Baby!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I add one? Do people really care what I’m up to now? I don’t know. But I’ve been growing a bit disenchanted with the state of the internet lately. It feels like a lot of people trying to squeeze posts in between ads on a handful of social networks. I miss when the internet was more distributed and a bit more personal and weird. This felt like a little push in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more about now pages check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://nownownow.com/about&quot; title=&quot;now! now! now!&quot;&gt;nownownow.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/now</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/now</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>And Or Not</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;tldr: I wrote and recorded a noisy, bass driven solo record. You should &lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/the-infernal-machine&quot;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 400px; height: 241px;&quot; src=&quot;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=165933545/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/artwork=small/transparent=true/&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/the-infernal-machine&quot;&gt;The Infernal Machine by And Or Not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I was listening to a lot of Death From Above 1979 and just got the urge to write some fast, high energy song with just bass, keys, drums and vocals. Sort of a cursed jazz trio. I was also looking to push my drumming, which has been a focus this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started just writing and recording a bunch of bass riffs when I had random nights free and then I’d come back later, narrowing down which riffs I liked the best. Because I was just writing on bass I felt like I ended up writing riffs differently than I would if I were writing on guitar. I felt more free to wander out of keys and write more chromatically, since I wouldn’t have to fit things in a larger chord structure. It was really a fun way to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there I started piecing together some basic song structure and trying to figure out what to write lyrics about. I tired to let the topics of these songs be a bit more “whatever popped into my head”, worrying less about having central, cohesive ideas. I ended up writing about social media (Black Box), people reminding me to eat well (Eat This, You’ll Live Forever), and our cat, who likes to hunt our children (Natural Predator).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had the song structures down I recorded bass (DIed into Logic with a fuzzy amp model) and then started really working on writing/recording drums. This project ended up being a good excuse to dive a little deeper into recording drums at home. I picked up a kick drum mic off of Craigslist, gathered a bunch of 57s to mike the snare and both toms, and used one of my condenser mics as an overhead. It had fun playing around with getting a decent sound and learned a bit about recording drums. My basement is not the best space to record, but I made due.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drums took me a long time to record. Part of this was nailing down exactly what the drum part should be and part of this was playing it right. I’m really glad I did all the tracks to a grid. It helped to be able to follow a click and punch in where I needed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the drums were finished I worked on vocals. I was probably most nervous about this part since vocals have never really been a strength of mine. I tried to just let go, project, be loud where it made sense, be a little screamy where it worked, and just commit. I also leaned into using a bit of fuzz on the vocals, which fit nicely with the aesthetic of these songs. All in all it turned out well. It’s certainly not the greatest vocal performance, but there isn’t much that feels bad or like the vocals detract too much from the songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While recording “Eat This, You’ll Live Forever” I had the kids come in and sing “Eat this!” and used their takes to build gang vocals in the outro. I’m really glad I got them involved and they seemed to really like hearing their vocals as I was mixing things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished up by adding some keys. Mainly synth or organ parts doing some countermelody or beefing up some parts. After that, a bit of mixing. I ended up doubling all the bass parts, one track with some fuzz/overdrive and another with a lower, cleaner sound to beef things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I came out with something that I was really proud of. This is the first time I’ve done a true solo record where I’ve played every instrument and done all the vocals (apart from some gang vocals by my kinds). I didn’t really know what to do with it so I just put it up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://andornot.bandcamp.com/album/the-infernal-machine&quot;&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; and sent the link around. I’d love for more people to listen to it, but honestly, I’m just happy I made it. And Or Not is a fun format, bass driven, high energy, so maybe I’ll do some more of these songs soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/and-or-not</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/and-or-not</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trackstar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many good projects come from scratching your own itch. I like to track thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years I’ve had on and off bursts of focus on practicing. Practicing guitar, drawing, chess, things like that. And I always find value in quantifying how often I’m practicing. I like to know how many hours per month, week, year, etc. I’ve spent on that skill. I feel like, as long as I’m practicing the right things, I can feel good about the progress if I can see a history of it. Plus wanting to see the numbers can help make sure I stick with things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past I was just writing simple Markdown docs and then ran a small Sinatra app that pulled metadata out of that directory and gave me some historical stats. I called that system &lt;a href=&quot;http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/one-year-of-input-coffee&quot;&gt;Input Coffee&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured I could automate things a bit more and build something a bit more reusable, so I decided to build a small command line based tracking app, &lt;strong&gt;Trackstar&lt;/strong&gt;.  I recognize that this type of interface only appeals to a very select group of people, but that group includes me, so I built it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a pretty simple idea. You use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;trackstar -n&lt;/code&gt; program to create a log directory, then (when you’re in that directory) just use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;trackstar&lt;/code&gt; command to make a new entry. It will prompt you for a few things; title, time, and some notes, then turn it into a Markdown file.  You can get some basic stats by running &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;trackstar -s&lt;/code&gt; (again, in the log directory).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty bare bones right now and I’d like to iterate a bit on the interface (I do thing command line apps can have nice interfaces). I’d also like to do a lot more around the stats, maybe even pull in the Sinatra app/web based visualizations of the data to get a better history, we’ll see. For now it’s kind of fun to keep it as a purely terminal interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole thing is just built in Ruby and could probably stand to be optimized a bit, but it was fun to build a gem that was a pure executable thing, rather than a library. You can check out the code and full instructions for how to use it on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dorkrawk/trackstar&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently dog fooding it by tracking my guitar practice. So far it’s working pretty well and I’m making tweaks as needed. If this scratches a specific itch you have, try it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/trackstar1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/trackstar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/trackstar</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recording Let &apos;er RIP!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the end of October I put out a 3 song record, Let ‘er RIP!, with my skath band, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/gravedangerskath&quot;&gt;Grave Danger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/let_er_rip_cover-500.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(It’s available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/5y1wpLaegWoOk2vJHVXAQS&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/album/let-er-rip-single/1440193477?app=apple%20music&quot;&gt;Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gravedangerskath.bandcamp.com&quot;&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/gravedangerskath/sets/let-er-rip/s-4XXAz&quot;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; and lots of other places!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote about some of the songwriting in &lt;a href=&quot;http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/starting-a-skath-band&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; but the recording process for this record was very different from anything else I’ve ever worked on. Since I was playing a lot of the instruments and we were never going to have everybody in the band all together at once it would be a really piecemeal process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rhythm Section&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Dane did some rough recordings of his drum parts using the demos I had created. This let me do my recording over a live drummer rather than programmed drums from Logic Pro. This really helped me get a better feel for the songs and made things feel much more organic. While I was recording over new drum parts I built the “working” versions of the songs from copies of the demos, that way I could just swap out the demo parts for final parts rather than having to build the song again from scratch. It was pretty cool to hear the songs evolve just by swapping in better recordings one instrument at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first work was laying down guitars. I actually ended up using the same amp model I used in the demos for the clean track but did all of the heavy guitar parts through my Dual Rectifier miced with a SM-57. I ended up double tracking almost all of the rhythm guitar parts (both clean and heavy) and I was really happy with the thickness that gave me. Most of the miced recording was done in my bedroom (which is carpeted) with the amp facing a closet full of clothes. The tracks for Too Ghoul For School were done in the garage (mainly to make it easier to record while Elliot napped) and they ended up having a harsher sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/guitar_recording.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bass work was pretty straightforward. I bough a DI box and recorded all my bass parts through that. I did take my bass (and old Washburn) to get tuned up before I did any of the recording and it really made a big difference. The keyboard work was also pretty cut and dry. I actually used some of the demo keyboard work for the final version (the first arpeggiated organ chord in Grave Danger, for example!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Horns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The horns were a little tricker. The horns in the demos were all done via keyboard and I needed to share the parts with the other horn players. For this I sat down with &lt;a href=&quot;https://musescore.org/en&quot;&gt;MuseScore&lt;/a&gt; (in awesome piece of free open source software fore creating sheet music) and transcribed all four horn parts. It was really cool to see the sheet music for my arrangements and I think it really helped Margret and Andy lay down the trombone and trumpet parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was doing the tenor and bari sax parts, but I only owned a tenor (which I had bough earlier this year, specifically for this project) so I needed to track down a bari. This was actually harder than I expected. At one point I emailed a local high school band teacher to see if the school could loan me one. Ultimately I had to rent one from a music shop about an hour away. I only had it for a week and that was still pretty expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recorded the tenor and bari parts and then sent Margret and Andy a mix of the songs with only the rhthym section and my sax parts so that they could record their parts on top of that. Dane set up some mics in his basement and over a few weekends they got all three songs done. I think this was a very new experience for them and it was awesome to hear all four horn parts together on real instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../blog_media/bari_sax_recording.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Drums (for real this time)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After recording the horns, it was time to do the REAL drum parts. After considering a few options we ended up going to Justin at &lt;a href=&quot;http://waysound.com/&quot;&gt;Waysound Studios&lt;/a&gt; for the drum tracking. I’ve worked with Justin on a lot of projects when I was in bands back in Chicago and he’s always fantastic. There’s actually a live recording of Dane tracking these songs, if you want to watch about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/waysoundrecording/videos/742118122792285/?hc_ref=ARTD5lMg7XDeavGHpR0jlWvzyGozJbSvIV5uImjKlz0ioUgewmWf0NyAJxEx02Yp_qA&amp;amp;__xts__[0]=68.ARBv2iwLhfRe1ChJ5oM-7XapGmtz0cpln6XciNQO-3m20WmDkx5O1kc0bv7VCato2idHb5SshOMOPRuE2B5cfLYRCfnIdxS9_DLBjknHr1bNr-GVsV2n1Qc05tnrk8tSwGNBHRlMSEYU7ZWMExtFeGcwXRbANNg1nXcs-e6if9tPghtrnyxTDFKcfzf0sPKC-YGVfwtQ6HrqvjH8OVBaaodng_kn9K9NxZDx-2SH7E2bpzFUotmySTB0cLL14HXnPUqXW8pAUawYn1px7cY_2yOtd8ISG_uqlXZ5xXkKhAu1pTOafUDajeYgwdq8wKxnUg3zD_P6CejU5aGfCaBZPA&amp;amp;__tn__=FC-R&quot;&gt;4 hours of drum recording&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drums turned out fantastic and added so much depth to the songs. Now it was time to do vocals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vocals (and everything else)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vocals were strange. I had an idea of how they should sort of sound in my head and I did the vocals on the demo, but I knew that Alan was the right person to sing for this record. The problem was that he was in Minnesota and  I was in California and we were only communicating through email. He did some rough demos of the vocals and I sent some notes back and then he recorded the final versions. The vocals were by far the weirdest thing to do remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted Josh and Chris to add harmonies so I just sent them a mix with Al’s vocals and let them just record a bunch of takes and send me whatever they had. I wanted to add a few background vocals parts, too so I set up a mic in the garage and layed down some of my own parts.  I ultimately just picked a bunch of stuff that sounded good and pieced it all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was blindly working with the vocalists, Dane and Emily were recording Emily’s synth and organ parts. I didn’t have these in mind when I was arranging the songs, but there are some synth parts that now seem like they obviously needed to be part of this music. They ended up being great additions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I wanted to get my family involved. First I had Eileen do some high harmonies and “oooo”s in Too Ghoul For School (which was ripe for vocal layering), then as I was mixing I heard Elliot repeating the work “ghoul” during the chorus, so I recording him and added his vocals into a few sections of Too Ghoul. It was really fun to be able to give him his first record credit before his second birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Putting It All Together&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I was sitting in front of three enormous Logic Pro projects with up to 60 tracks a piece. I was not remotely qualified to mix what would probably be a 9 or 10 piece band so again we turned to Justin at Waysound. After fooling around with some clever exporting techniques, I ended up just removing any EQ and effects from all the tracks and exporting them all to WAV files and then sending those over to him so he could work his magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole recording, mixing, and mastering process took almost a year (with my “solo” recording using up the bulk of that time) but we had a finished product before our self imposed deadline of Halloween.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recording the record in this way had its advantages. I liked being able to work at my own pace and on my own schedule (which was really important with a kid). The process of migrating the demo into a final version piece by piece made it easier to work on my own, since I never had to bootstrap the songs from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really hard to work in isolation though. I’m used to being in the studio with other people who can provide feedback and keep me from getting in my own head about guitar tone. I missed the comradery of hanging out in the studio with friends. I augmented this by texting Dane a lot during the process. Technically, if I did this again, I’d be more diligent about making sure EVERYTHING lined up with a click track from day one. When pulling in parts from many different sources, having one source of truth for timing is really important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t overstate how much fun I had making these three goofy songs with a bunch of friends. Even though they’re ridiculous in subject, they really mean a lot to me and I loved the process working on them. I already have the seeds for several more Grave Danger songs and I’m excited to work on new material!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t heard the record yet, please take a listen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;&quot; src=&quot;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3029029663/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gravedangerskath.bandcamp.com/album/let-er-rip&quot;&gt;Let &amp;#39;er RIP! by Grave Danger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/recording-let-er-rip</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dinosaurseateverybody.com/blog/recording-let-er-rip</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
